She wasn't hitting you
這哪是打你
but me.
這分明就是在打我
Your Highness, don't mind it.
三公主 不必介懷
It didn't hurt when she whipped me.
這鞭子打在身上 不疼
But if
但是若
you're angered,
惹三公主動怒
my heart
我蘇沐
will ache.
會心疼的
Don't! Don't!
別別別
Please don't be like this!
別 別這樣
I know you are reluctant to stay at the Music and Dance Academy.
我知道你待在教坊司實屬無奈
And you are tired of putting on a fake smile every day.
你也不願意每天過賠笑的日子
From now on,
從現在開始
you don't have to play up to me.
你在我面前不必百般討好
Just see me as your friend.
你把我當朋友看待就好
I can't take your flirting anymore.
總撩我也頂不住啊
How could I dare do that?
這怎麼可以
I'm just a musician
小人身為一介樂人
with low status.
身份低微
I dare not
怎敢與三公主
befriend Your Highness.
以朋友相稱
But you didn't choose to be a musician.
樂人又不是你選的
If possible,
要是可以的話
who wouldn't want to be
誰不想像裴恆一樣
born in a noble family
出身就是名門望族
and enjoy a wealthy life like Pei Heng?
不用為生計發愁
After all, it's my fault.
說到底 是我的錯
Your Highness, please don't blame yourself.
三公主切莫自責
The small wounds are no big deal.
這些小傷不打緊
But as for these rewards,
但是這些賞賜
I
蘇沐
no longer dare receive.
是不敢再收了
Zi Rui,
梓銳
if you go back,
你回去
Lin Qi may give you a hard time again.
林七可能還會再為難你的
But I belong to the Music and Dance Academy.
可小人畢竟還是教坊司的人哪
I've decided to give you the gifts,
我陳芊芊送出去的禮物
how can I take them back?
哪有退回來的道理
No.
不行
I have to talk to Lin Qi!
我得找林七理論理論
Your Highness!
三公主
The Crown Princess Election will take place soon.
少城主的擢考在即
It's better to avoid unnecessary trouble.
咱多一事不如少一事
If Her Majesty blames you for...
這城主又怪罪下來
I don't care about the Crown Princess Election at all!
我才不在乎什麼少城主擢考呢
Your Highness!
三公主
Well...
這
Chen Qianqian will like that?
陳芊芊會喜歡這東西
After all, you two were brought together because of a horse.
畢竟您二人是因馬結緣
Makes sense.
也是
(Yueli Mansion) Since she likes me,
既然心悅於我
she'll be happy
我送什麼
with whatever I give to her.
她便會喜歡什麼
Young Master Han.
韓少君
Is the Third Princess inside?
三公主可在府中
Young Master.
回韓少君
Su Mu was just here.
剛才蘇沐蘇公子來過
Then Her Highness and he rushed
三公主隨他急匆匆地
to the Music and Dance Academy together.
往教坊司去了
The Music and Dance Academy?
教坊司
Young Master.
少君
You just said that she was in love with you.
您不是說她對您情根深種嗎
Then why would she go to the Music and Dance Academy?
怎麼會去教坊司呢
When women misbehave,
女人不聽話
you need to correct them.
得多加管束才行
Right! That's right!
對 對對對
You want to buy Su Mu?
你要買蘇沐
Yes.
沒錯
Tell me,
那你說說
why?
你為什麼要買蘇沐啊
For him,
你為了他
you not only come to the Academy frequently,
隔三岔五地來教坊司不夠
but also wanna buy him so that you can see him every day.
還要把他買回去日日相看
You already have
你府裡
Han Shuo in your mansion, don't you?
不是已經有一個韓爍了嗎
He's not good enough?
是他不好
I want to buy Su Mu,
我要蘇沐
not because I want him to entertain me,
並不是想要把他接到府中取樂
but because he doesn't want to stay at the Academy.
蘇沐不想待在教坊司
I redeem him so that he can get his freedom back.
我替他贖身是想還他自由
As for Han Shuo,
至於韓爍
would you stop working against him
你能不能不要因為我
because of me?
老是跟他對著幹啊
He's not a pushover as you think.
他不是你想的那樣好欺負
He's good at Kung Fu and tactical skills.
他有武藝 有謀略
He's just suffering from heart disease right now.
只是被心疾所困
Don't always look down upon him.
你別總是看不起他
Who do you think
你看我這兒
would want to be a musician here?
有幾個人想當樂人的
Don't pretend to be nice.
你裝什麼活菩薩
With Su Mu's reputation,
就蘇沐現在這個名聲
where else can he go?
他能去哪兒啊
Without you by his side,
離了你
anybody can bully him.
誰都可以欺壓他
Where can he go?
他能去哪兒安身呀
I've had a place for him.
我已經為他想好去處了
Anyway,
反正
it's none of your business.
用不著你管
Thanks!
謝謝
Young Master.
少君
Su Mu is just a musician.
你說這蘇沐不過是一名樂人
Why is the Third Princess willing to offend the Lins for him?
三公主為何為了他和林家作對
This rumored the Third Princess
這傳聞中的三公主啊
is getting more and more interesting.
當真是越來越有意思了
More and more interesting?
越來越有意思
What do you mean?
是 是什麼意思
She could apologize to me that night,
那晚她能低頭向我道歉
it shows she isn't as arrogant and bossy as the rumor says.
看來並非傳聞中的囂張跋扈
In fact, she's quite cute.
反倒乖巧可愛
And today, she was able to come up with a line for the poem,
今日又能對上風花雪月
which means she's not as illiterate as people think.
也並非傳聞中的目不識丁
She is now trying to save Su Mu,
如今她救蘇沐於水火
so she's not a heartless person as we heard.
也並非傳聞中的暴虐成性
She's actually nice and kind.
實則單純善良
When you think about it, it's really true.
這麼一想還 真是
The Third Princess only asked for a musician.
三公主不過是想要一個樂人
Yet Lin Qi refused her.
林七居然敢不給她
Then I'll make all the musicians
那就讓林七手裡的樂人
around Lin Qi disappear.
一個都不剩
So, should we kill the musicians
那我們是把樂人都殺了
or set the Academy on fire?
還是把教坊司給點了
Your Majesty.
城主
the Third Princess is young
三公主正值妙齡
and in good health.
身體強健
But I have heart problems,
而韓某卻患有心疾
and I won't live long.
命不久矣
I feel so sorry.
韓某愧不能當
Your Majesty, I hope you can give an order
特請城主下令
to send all musicians of the Academy
將教坊司樂人
to the Third Princess's mansion
一併送入三公主府
to play music and sing for her,
給她彈琴唱曲
so that she won't be lonely.
消遣寂寞
Young Master Han,
韓少君
you should talk to the Third Princess.
你應該好言規勸三公主
How can we send all musicians
怎能讓樂人
to Yueli Mansion?
都進入月璃府呢
I know I don't have many days left.
韓某自知時日無多
I can't accompany Her Highness all the time.
無法常伴三公主左右
As long as Her Highness is happy,
但只要三公主開心
even if I die someday,
就算韓某有一天離她而去了
I won't have any regrets!
也無憾
Since you've made your mind,
既然韓少君心意已決
I'll grant your request.
那便允了
From this day on,
即日
the musicians of the Academy
叫教坊司的樂人
will move to Yueli Mansion.
住進月璃府吧
Thank you, Your Majesty!
謝城主
Your Highness, about this matter...
三公主 你看這個事
Your Highness!
三公主
I thought you only had Su Mu in your heart.
小人還以為您心裡只有蘇沐呢
But, I was brought here, too.
這不 把小人也帶來了
Stop!
停
I...
我
Your Highness!
三公主
What's going on?
這是什麼情況
I heard it was an order from Her Majesty.
據說是城主下的令
We'll belong to Yueli Mansion from now on.
我們以後就都歸月璃府了
Greetings to Your Highness!
見過三公主
Miss Lin Qi!
林七小姐
Miss Lin Qi, you are so generous!
林七小姐可真是高風亮節
You didn't want the money,
給錢你不要
and now,
這不
your business is banned!
依法取締了
You...
你
She'll hit me!
她打我
I... I hit you?
我 我打你
Miss Lin.
林小姐
What?
怎麼
Came to Yueli Mansion to make trouble?
要來月璃府撒野了嗎
She's Her Majesty's daughter.
她是城主女兒
I'm fine if she strong-arms me.
處處壓我一頭也就算了
But who do you think you are?
你算個什麼東西
How dare you to challenge me?
也敢跟我叫板
I remember
我記得
that you used to use whip, too.
你也用鞭子
Never mind!
不了 不了
That was ancient history already.
那都是老皇曆了
Having you is good enough for me now.
我現在有你就夠了
Catch!
接著
Fine!
好
Yueli Mansion!
月璃府
I'll remember what you did to me today!
這筆賬 我林七記下了
Lin Qi!
林七
You can take the other musicians back.
其他樂人你都帶走吧
I only want Su Mu.
我只留蘇沐
Your Highness.
三公主
Young Master Han even
韓少君為了這幾個樂人
lowered himself for these musicians.
不惜自輕自賤
And now,
現在啊
people all say that you two, as a couple,
市井都傳言 你們夫妻倆
one dares to ask,
一個敢要
and the other dares to take.
一個敢收
He sacrificed so much for you.
他為你犧牲了這麼多
So, just keep
這幾個樂人
these musicians to yourself.
自己留著用吧
You asked my mother
是你向母親
to send these musicians here?
要來這些樂人在府上的
And you also
你還
lowered yourself?
自輕自賤了
As a woman,
你一個女人家的
why did you ask that?
問這事做什麼
You didn't feel embarrassed to tell,
你也好意思往外說
why would I feel embarrassed to hear?
我怎麼就不好意思往裡聽了呢
I...
我
Your Highness!
三公主
Where should I accommodate so many people?
這麼多人往哪兒擱呢
Young Master, greetings to you!
屬下拜見少君
Rise.
起來吧
Young Master is indeed clever!
少君英明
You came up with this idea,
能想到如此辦法
so that I could see you with no trouble.
讓小人名正言順地與少君相見
But...
只是
Sorry that I'm incompetent.
恕小人無能
I've spied in Huayuan City for years,
潛伏在花垣城多年
but still haven't found the Dragon Bone.
竟沒有打探到龍骨的下落
However, my clients
但是小人接待的恩客
are all high-ranking officials and noblemen.
都是達官貴族
About how much money in the treasury,
這花垣城有多少存銀
how many troops and provisions the City Guards own,
護城軍有多少兵馬糧草
even the health condition of the City Owner,
還有那花垣城主的身體狀況如何
I know them all!
我可是無一不知 無一不曉
Young Master, what do you want to ask?
少君 您想知道什麼
Just go ahead and ask me!
您儘管問
What did Chen Qianqian do
陳芊芊以前去你們那兒
when she visited the Academy before?
都幹些什麼
Young Master!
少君
I heard
聽聞
that the Second Princess
教坊司的那些樂人
took all the musicians away.
都被二郡主給收了
What?
什麼
I just heard that.
是剛聽說的
Forget about the writing.
還寫什麼
Chuchu has become
楚楚近日來
so lazy recently.
越來越懈怠
She hangs out with the people of the Music and Dance Academy every day.
整日與教坊司的人混在一起
That'll only diminish her.
還能有什麼好名聲
It's such a waste that I've done so much for her.
枉費我為她鋪路許久啊
Your Majesty, don't be angry.
城主息怒
I heard that the Third Princess has been very well behaved.
聽聞 三公主最近有所收斂
Even the only musician in her mansion
府中的一位樂人
will be sent away soon.
也馬上就要送走了
Is that so?
竟有此事
It appears that she's doing it for Young Master Han.
似乎 是為了韓少君
Young Master,
少君
why did you give all the musicians
您為何要將除蘇沐以外的樂人
to the Second Princess, except for Su Mu?
轉贈給二郡主呢
So that our spies
自然是為了讓我們的探子
can continue to do their job.
繼續打探消息
Young Master is indeed clever!
少君英明啊
I thought
小的還以為
you wanted to make the Third Princess look good,
您是想給三公主造勢
so you sent the musicians to the Second Princess
故意送一些樂人到二郡主府上
to ruin her reputation.
敗壞她的名聲
But no matter what,
但是不管怎麼說
you got Su Mu for the Third Princess,
您為三公主求得蘇沐
she must be thankful for you.
三公主心裡感激您
I heard
我聽說
that she spent a lot of money on a Guqin.
三公主花重金尋得一把古琴
I think it's a gift for you.
想必是送給少君的謝禮
She rarely does things particularly for me.
難得陳芊芊想討我歡心
When she comes later to drop off the gift,
一會兒她來送東西
we need to act surprised
咱們裝出很驚喜的樣子
to make her feel good.
成全她的這份心意
And don't tell her
也別告訴她
that I don't play Qin.
我不會撫琴
You are so thoughtful, Young Master!
少君考慮得周到
Young Master!
少君
Your Highness!
三公主
Young Master is over here!
我們少君在這兒呢
Morning!
早上好
And?
還有呢
I heard you cough.
剛剛聽到少君咳嗽了
Take good care and drink more warm water.
注意身體 多喝熱水啊
Do you think Pei Heng will like this Qin?
你說裴恆能喜歡我送這把琴嗎
Of course not.
當然不會了
He hates playing the Qin.
裴司學特別討厭彈琴
Don't you remember
您忘了
that when you were little,
在您小的時候
in order to show the power of the women in Huayuan,
每逢佳節宴請
he was asked to play the Qin on site
都會要求裴司學現場彈琴
at the feast of every festival?
以示咱們花垣女子的威嚴
So, he...
所以人家
So, it has
所以就
left a scar on his heart?
留下心理陰影了
That's right.
那可不嗎
No wonder he hates me so much.
怪不得這麼討厭我
Then I should really give him this Qin.
那我就更得送琴給他了
Bai Ji.
白芨
Whom did you say
你剛才說
this Qin was for?
琴是送給誰的
Please give me another chance
請再給屬下一個
to fix my mistake!
將功補過的機會吧
You...
你
You know
你應該知道
that I never liked Qin.
我從小最不喜歡的就是琴
Really?
是嗎
You can fool others,
你騙得了別人
but not me.
你可騙不了我
Playing the Qin can help you express your feelings.
彈琴能夠抒發性情
It's your favorite hobby.
你最喜歡了
The Qin I brought to you was made by a great master.
我送你的這個琴可是名師製作
The best Qin should be played by the best player.
好琴配佳音嘛
Listen to me.
我跟你說
You need to stick to what you like.
你要做自己喜歡做的事情
I'm happy if you are happy.
你開心我就會開心的
I know
我知道
people all think
所有人都認為
that only musicians like to play the Qin to please women.
只有樂人才喜歡彈琴取悅女人
You don't want people to think of you that way,
你不願意被世俗束縛
so you'd rather not play.
寧願不彈
And you pretend that you don't like it at all,
還假裝出一副不喜歡的樣子
because you don't want to be a pleasing tool.
是不願意成為取悅別人的工具
A knowledgeable,
像你這種
righteous, smart and talented
學識豐富 品行端莊
person like you,
又有頭腦 又有才華的人
shouldn't care too much
根本就不應該在乎
about what people think.
這些世俗的眼光
Actually,
其實
Su Mu is just like you.
蘇沐也是一樣
He doesn't want to stay at the Academy...
他並不想待在教坊司
It's okay!
沒事
Just think about it.
你考慮考慮
No matter you'll keep Su Mu or not,
不管你最後願不願意留下蘇沐
I hope you can stick to your heart
我都希望你能夠遵從本心
and do what you want to do.
做你自己喜歡做的事情
How was it?
怎麼樣了
Has he made a decision?
決定了嗎
Has Minister Pei said yes?
裴司學答應了沒呀
Your Highness.
三公主
I'm already very thankful
三公主能有這份心意
for your thoughtfulness.
小的已經是感激不盡了
If you
這日後
can go to the Academy
若三公主有空
to visit me every now and then in the future,
能常去那教坊司看看小的
that'll be good enough for me.
就可以了
Pei Heng will let you stay!
裴恆留下你了
Chen Qianqian!
陳芊芊
Did you force him to play again?
你又逼他彈琴
Don't you feel ashamed?
你還有沒有點廉恥心
Stay away from Minister Pei!
離裴司學遠點
Qianqian!
芊芊
I thought you went to meet your bosom friend.
三公主不是去會知音了嗎
What?
怎麼
You hurt your arm from playing the Qin?
彈琴廢胳膊
Can't believe you are mocking me while I'm in pain.
我都這樣了你還說風涼話
Your arm is dislocated.
你這是脫臼了
I need to reset your arm.
需要把關節復位
When I pop it in place, it'll hurt a little.
一會兒我發力的時候會有點疼
Hang in there.
你忍著點
Hurt?
疼
Your Highness, don't you remember?
大郡主 你可別忘了啊
The Third Princess began to practice Kung Fu from an early age.
我們三公主從小習武
She fell from a horse when she was seven,
七歲從馬背上掉下
fell from a roof when she was ten.
十歲從房頂上摔下
She even broke her legs more than once,
雙腿摔斷了都不止一次
and she never complained.
哼都沒哼的一聲
So, there's no way that this little arm problem will hurt her!
這小小的脫臼就還疼
I remember.
我沒忘
Your Highness, don't worry!
大郡主 別怕啊
Just go ahead
你就放心大膽地
and reset her arm,
給我們三公主接回去啊
no matter how hurt it'll be.
多疼都沒事啊
Zi Rui, you know me so well!
梓銳 你真瞭解我
Good for you!
真行
Of course!
那是
Then I'll start now.
那我要用力了
Hold on!
等一下
Will you please say something
要不然你們說點什麼
to distract me?
轉移下我的注意力
Though I'm fat,
雖然我胖
I'm still afraid of pain!
但是我 也怕疼
What... What are you doing?
你 你幹什麼
I've sent them out.
我讓他們都出去了
Are you sure you can do this?
能行嗎你
I'm your husband. You don't trust me?
我是你夫君 你信不過我
How's that relevant to this?
這有什麼必然聯繫嗎
When we first met,
那日你我初見
you were in red dress and looked so gorgeous.
三公主一襲紅衣 英姿颯爽
Even though your horse was out of control and you almost fell,
縱然馬匹失控 險些墜馬
you stayed calm and came through.
也處變不驚 化險為夷
Your bravery in crisis
三公主臨危不懼的模樣
made me fall in love with you right away.
令韓某一見傾心
I vowed that I'd marry nobody but you.
立誓 此生非三公主不可
I know
我也知道
that you love me deeply.
三公主對我一往情深
I feel the same to you.
我亦是如此
Isn't that "Humph" a little too careless?
你這個哼也太敷衍了吧
Who said I was careless?
誰說我敷衍了
Done!
好了
It's done?
這 這就好了
So,
所以
you only said those things
韓少君剛剛說的那些話
to distract me.
只是想轉移我的注意力
That's why you talked nonsense.
才說的那些鬼話
Since you are so afraid of pain,
既然這麼怕疼
why have you been
為什麼從小到大
pretending that you were not?
還要裝作不怕疼的樣子
I am not!
本來就不怕啊
It's not quite done yet.
好像還差了一點啊
I need to readjust a bit.
我重新調整一下
No! Stop it!
不 不了不了
I am afraid.
怕
I am.
怕了
I had to pretend because of the tough situation.
這是形勢逼人 不得不
I'm the Third Princess, after all.
畢竟我是三公主
Since Zi Rui believes that I'm not afraid, I'll go with it.
那梓銳說不怕 那就不怕吧
You are so nosy!
多事
You can all come in now!
你們都進來吧
Why did Lin Qi
你們說這林七
strike a surprise attack on me?
為什麼要偷襲我
Because she knew she couldn't defeat me!
那還不是因為正面打不過
We've had so many fights since we were little.
從小到大跟她打了這麼多場架
I've never been defeated.
我哪一場輸過給她
After I'm recovered,
等我養好了
I'll go teach her a lesson!
我就去收拾她
Yuanyuan,
長姐
how long will it take for me to recover?
我這還得養多久
Young Master did a good job.
少君復位得很好
With your health condition,
以你的體質
you are fine already.
當下就沒有什麼大問題了
Already!
當下
Al...
當
Your Highness,
三公主
I'll go invite Miss Lin Qi right now.
我現在就去請林七小姐
Wait!
等等
Forget it!
算了算了算了
I'm the daughter of Her Majesty.
我畢竟是城主的女兒
I'll be a bigger person.
我大人有大量
I won't make a big deal out of it.
怎麼會跟這種小民計較呢
Zi Rui,
梓銳
do you remember
你還記得嗎
that my mother taught us to work hard.
母親教導我人要上進
The Crown Princess Election is right around the corner.
如今少城主擢考在即
I'd rather spend time on study
我收拾她那工夫
than waste time on her!
我不如多看兩頁書
Don't you think?
你說對不對
I'm letting her off.
放了她
Young Master,
少君
the new spies are in place already.
新的暗樁已經安排妥當
We are investigating around the city
我正在全城調查
into who made the bamboo tube.
是誰制定了火漆竹筒
I'm sure we'll find out
很快就會知道
who was behind it soon.
誰在背後搗鬼
One more thing.
還有個事
The spy we once put in the Academy
之前安插在教坊司的探子
found out something after
被送到二郡主府上之後
he was sent to the Second Princess's mansion.
探聽到一些消息
He wants to talk to you in person.
想找您當面商議
Do you have time to meet him now?
您看 現在叫來可好
I'll hit you!
打你
Chen Qianqian, how come you are so cute?
陳芊芊 你怎麼這麼可愛呢
Young Master?
少君
Sure, bring him here.
行 你帶他來見我
Yes.
是
So cute!
可愛
Thank you for your compliment, Young Master!
謝少君誇獎
Young Master, greetings to you!
見過少君
What's the emergency?
何事這麼著急
I suddenly remembered a secret rumor.
小人偶然想起城中祕聞
Maybe it'll help you to get the Dragon Bone.
或許 可助少君奪得龍骨
Tell me.
說
The Second Princess Chen Chuchu isn't Her Majesty's real daughter.
二郡主陳楚楚非城主親生
What?
什麼
Chen Chuchu isn't her real daughter?
陳楚楚非城主所生
And Chen Yuanyuan is disabled.
陳沅沅又身患殘疾
So, Chen Qianqian will be
那花垣城的繼承人
the only successor of Huayuan City!
就只剩下陳芊芊一人了
Young Master,
少君
if we poison Chen Qianqian,
只要我們毒殺陳芊芊
Her Majesty will certainly save her with the Dragon Bone.
城主必定拿出龍骨相救
That'll be our chance to take it,
我們趁機奪下龍骨
and your heart disease will be cured finally!
您的心疾就可以治癒了
Then...
那
What about Chen Qianqian?
陳芊芊呢
Chen...
陳
The Dragon Bone can only save one person.
龍骨只能救一人性命
Chen Qianqian will die for sure.
陳芊芊必死無疑呀
Based on what I heard,
屬下探聽得知
Her Majesty already had a sign of stroke.
花垣城主已有中風前兆
If
倘若
she knows that her favorite daughter died a violent death,
她得知自己最疼愛的女兒橫死
she'll be destroyed,
必將心智大亂
and Huayuan City will become leaderless.
花垣也將群龍無首
By then,
到時候
you'll be recovered,
少君病癒
and we'll have no worries at all.
我們便再無忌憚
We can swing south and conquer Huayuan.
便可揮師南下 攻佔花垣
And the black stone mine in Huayuan...
那時候 花垣的烏石礦
Young Master!
少君
Smelting is the foundation of our Xuanhu City.
冶煉是我們玄虎城的立城之本
Black stone mine is extremely important to us!
烏石礦對我們尤為重要
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity!
這可是天賜良機
You have to make a decision!
您得拿個主意呀
I need more time to think about it.
此事還得從長計議
We can't rush it.
切莫操之過急
Here you go.
給你
Naughty!
頑皮
-Again! -Do it again!
再來 再來
How's your arm?
你胳膊怎麼樣了
My arm? It's fine now!
胳膊啊 早沒事了
Han Shuo cured me.
韓爍給我治好了
Good to know!
那就好
The fruits were just delivered
這是剛剛從玄虎城
from Xuanhu City.
運來的時令水果
I brought some for you.
我拿來給你嚐嚐鮮
Then I have to eat now.
那我得趕緊吃
In case Han Shuo sees them.
可別讓韓爍給看見
I can ask the servant to give him some, too.
我讓下人再給韓少君送一份
You don't understand.
不是
I'm worried that he'll be homesick
我是怕他看到家鄉的水果
if he sees the fruits from his hometown.
思念家人
I'm being inconsiderate.
是我思慮不周了
Young Master Han lives in Huayuan alone.
韓少君孤身一人待在花垣
He must be very sad.
他心裡一定不好受
Not necessarily.
那應該沒有
He only has the Dragon Bone in his mind.
他心裡只想著龍骨
Have a good night's sleep.
你早些歇息
I'll visit you again in a few days.
過幾日 我再來看你
Okay!
好
Young Master.
少君
Your Highness.
三公主
I saw that Young Master Han just left,
我剛剛看到韓少君離開
and he seemed unhappy.
好像有一點不太開心
Oh, no!
完了
Maybe he heard me!
他不會都聽到了吧
He must have been jealous.
那肯定吃醋了唄
Before, when you
想當初啊
broke your arm or leg,
你摔斷胳膊摔斷腿的時候
Minister Pei never visited you.
都沒見裴司學來看望過
And now it was just a shoulder dislocation.
你現在只不過是小小的脫臼
That's because of the friendship between teacher and student.
那是師生情誼
The friendship between teacher and student.
師生情誼
If we poison Chen Qianqian,
殺了三公主
Her Majesty will certainly save her with the Dragon Bone.
城主必定拿出龍骨相救
Hey,
你說
Han Shuo stays in our mansion,
韓爍現在住在我們府裡
so he's one of us.
也就是我們府上的人
We should have him
我們是不是得讓他感受一下
feel like home.
家的溫暖
Your Highness, you mean...
三公主 你的意思是
How about we hold a birthday party for him?
給他操辦一次生辰怎麼樣
Young Master's birthday date is a top secret.
少君的生辰是上等的機密
How can we find out?
我們 從何而知呢
You know what?
你不懂
About Han Shuo's birthday date, five elements and eight characters,
韓爍哪天出生 五行八字
horoscope and blood type,
星座 血型
I know them even better than his mom!
我比他媽都清楚
Look at you!
你說你
You useless jerk!
你這個敗家玩意兒
I'll teach you a lesson when we are home!
看我回去怎麼收拾你
Hurry!
走
Listen,
你聽我說
eating one onion every day
每天吃個洋蔥
will guarantee you a daughter.
保準能生個女兒來
So your mother-in-law won't abuse you anymore.
你也不用受你那惡婆婆的氣了
Really?
真的嗎
Of course!
對呀
Take it.
拿著
Five coins.
五文錢啊
The vegetables are here.
菜來了
Just these two.
就這兩個
Look! Look!
你看看 你看看
He's exposing his legs in public!
光天化日穿得這麼暴露
How shameless!
傷風敗俗
He should make a living in the Music and Dance Academy!
這還不如直接去教坊司賣藝去呢
So embarrassing!
真丟人
If he is taken advantage of,
這要是被人輕薄了
he should only blame himself!
都怪他自己不知檢點
-He deserves it! -That's right!
活該他 就是 對
-He deserves it! -Let's go!
活該 走走走
What do you think
你說
we should give to Han Shuo?
咱倆送韓爍點什麼好
Why don't you ask your advisers?
你為何不問你那幾個幕僚呢
They are only interested
那些先生就只知道
in talented scholars and pretty ladies.
才子佳人那一套
Their ideas will only be limited to handkerchief, fan, sachet or jade pendant.
無非就是手帕 扇子 香囊 玉佩
Too old-fashioned!
俗
I heard
我聽說
that women in Xuanhu City
玄虎城的女人
would make shoes and socks for their husbands.
會親自為自己的夫婿縫製鞋襪
Shoes?
鞋
Men always love shoes!
自古男人都是喜歡鞋
Then I'll buy shoes for him.
那就送鞋
Is there a custom shop?
這兒有定製店嗎
Yes.
有
Please come again.
那記得再來啊
Okay!
好
Introduce some clients to me! Take care!
幫我介紹顧客 慢走
Warning! Be careful!
前方高能預警
Well... What are they hiding from?
這 他們躲什麼呀
The city patrol is here?
巡城的來了
You never paid when you bought things.
你買東西總是刷臉賒賬的
We owe money to the entire street.
整條街我們都欠著款呢
They are hiding from me?
躲我呢
Because they don't have manners.
那是他們不懂事
I will give you money, alright?
我給錢還不行嗎
We'll pay cash!
現金結款了
Open your doors!
趕緊開張啊
Come to my shop! Come on!
來我家買 來我家買
Your Highness, take a look!
三公主 快看
I have some new calligraphy and paintings.
我們家新進了一批字畫
Your Highness, we have new cloth!
三公主 我家新進了一批布
Come on! Take a look!
快來看 快來看呀
Your Highness!
三公主 三公主
Come and take a look at our lanterns. We have multiple colors.
看一下我們家燈籠 好多顏色
You only have cages, but no birds, right?
你這隻有籠也沒有鳥 是不是
Your Highness, what do you want to buy?
三公主想買點什麼
Come in and take a look!
進去看看
If there's anything you like, we'll deliver it to your mansion.
選好了立馬給您送到府上去
We have a lot of stuff.
裡面好多東西呢
Take a look inside.
進去看看
Please, come in!
請 請 請
You are back!
回來了
Are you worried that I collude with Xuanhu
三公主是擔心韓某與玄虎勾結
and exchange letters?
互通信件
Would you believe me if I told you
我 我說是竹筒先動的手
that the bamboo tube started it?
你能信嗎
You must be kidding.
三公主說笑了
Now, forget it.
不跟你玩了
I'm here for a reason.
我今天是來辦正事
Close your eyes.
你把眼睛閉上
Did I do anything
韓某最近是做了什麼事
that made you mad,
惹三公主不悅
so that you want to get rid of me?
想要除之而後快
No!
不是
It's not like what you thought.
不是你想的那樣
I kinda wish that you were here to kill me.
我倒是希望你是來殺我的
What did you say?
你說什麼
I'm not in the mood to joke.
我現在無心與你玩鬧
I see that you've been upset these couple of days.
我覺得你這兩天心情不太好
Is it because of me?
不會是因為我吧
No.
不是
How do I measure his chest and waist?
這胸圍跟腰圍怎麼量啊
I want to kill her,
我想著要殺她
but she is so innocent
她卻天真無邪
that she's even hugging me?
對我投懷送抱
Okay! I'm good now! Bye!
行了 沒事了 忙吧
The Third Princess
我們家三公主啊
really liked the cloth
看過你們家送過來的布料
that your shop delivered.
特別喜歡
We'll buy from your shop again.
下次還用你們家的啊
I also brought
小的這次前來
something else this time.
還帶了一些別的東西
A few days ago,
前幾日
you asked us
您在我們鋪子上
to make a custom-made sealing wax bamboo tube.
定製了一枚火漆竹筒
My boss said
我們掌櫃的說了
the Third Princess never ordered anything in small amount,
三公主哪做過這麼小的生意啊
so we made 500.
所以就做了五百個
The extra 499
這餘下的四百九十九枚竹筒呢
will be given to the Third Princess
都是我們東家的一點心意
for free.
還請三公主笑納
Alright.
那行吧
Then I'll take them on behalf of the Third Princess.
那我就替我們三公主收下了
Okay.
好
Now, you guys,
來 你們幾個
take them to the kitchen in the back yard.
搬到後院廚房去
See you!
告辭了
Okay.
好
Careful!
輕點
If we poison Chen Qianqian,
殺了三公主
Her Majesty will certainly save her with the Dragon Bone.
城主必定拿出龍骨相救
I don't care for it at all!
我才不稀罕呢
You finally smiled!
你終於笑了
Happy birthday to Young Master Han!
祝韓少君生日快樂
Happy birthday!
生日快樂
Today is my birthday?
今晚我的生辰
How did you know that?
你如何得知今天是我生辰
Not only do I know your birthday date,
我不僅知道今天是你的生辰
I also know you are 186cm in height,
我還知道你身高一八六
you weigh 75 kg,
七十五公斤
your blood type is O.
O型血
You like black,
喜歡黑色
don't like rainy days,
不喜歡下雨天
your favorite food is noodle soup cooked by your mom,
最喜歡吃你母親煮的清湯掛麵
you don't like ginger.
不喜歡吃薑
What else do you know?
你還知道什麼呀
I also know
我還知道
that when you were born,
自你出生以來
everyone in Xuanhu City
玄虎城上上下下
said that you'd be a rarely-seen prodigy.
都說你是百年難遇的奇才
But unfortunately, when you were 16,
可就偏偏在十六歲
you were diagnosed with heart disease.
被診出患有心疾
The doctors said
大夫們都說你
that you would die before 20.
活不過二十歲生辰
Ever since then,
自那個時候開始
your character has changed.
你就性情大變
What would the life be like
一個知道自己死期的人
for a man who knows when he'll die?
過的是什麼日子
It's like countdown every day.
每天都像是在倒數
You blame God for his unfairness.
你怨上天不公
You hate that you can't change your fate.
你恨無力改變
You want to live.
你想活著
So you'd rather do anything
所以只要能夠治癒心疾
as long as you can cure your disease.
什麼事你都肯做
Han Shuo,
韓爍
trust me,
你要相信
there's one person who can cure you,
有一個人能夠治癒你的
and she'll be the one who loves you the most.
她會是最愛你的人
So, don't give up!
所以不要氣餒
You have to stick it out to the end!
一定要堅持到最後
When people learned
所有人在得知
that I would die before 20,
我活不過二十歲的時候
they all tried to comfort me,
都勸我想開些
as if I were already dead.
彷彿我已經是個死人
But you actually believe that I can be saved.
你居然相信我還有救
Because you didn't meet me before.
那是因為你還沒有遇見我
Why do you give me that look again?
怎麼又是這個表情啊
You've been upset for days.
這幾天你總是愁眉不展的
You looked much better when you smiled just now.
像剛剛那樣笑起來多好看
Does it matter
我笑或不笑
whether I smile or not?
有那麼重要嗎
Of course, it does.
當然重要了
If a beauty doesn't smile under the moon,
月下美人若是不笑
then the staggering night view
豈不辜負
will be a waste.
美景良宵
Sounds like
這麼說來
Your Highness wants to spend the night with me.
三公主想與韓某共度良宵
I am spending the night with you right now, aren't I?
這不正在共度嗎
It's hotpot.
火鍋
Young Master, please.
來 少君 請
No matter what is bothering you,
不管你是因為什麼事情感到難過
nothing cannot be solved by one hotpot meal.
沒有什麼是一頓火鍋解決不了的
If there is,
如果有的話
then have two hotpot meals!
那就兩頓
What kind of theory is that?
這是什麼歪理
This is the law of hotpot!
這是火鍋法則
The second rule of this law
這法則的第二句就是
is that if you want to test
檢驗一個人
a person's real heart,
是不是對另外一個人真心
then you can see if she'll give you
就看她燙的東西第一口
the first thing she cooked.
要不要讓給他
This is the first thing I cooked.
第一個
I'll give it to you.
讓給你
I have heart disease.
我患有心疾
I can't eat spicy things.
吃不了辣
It's okay.
沒事
I like spicy food. I can eat it.
我愛吃辣 我能吃辣
Luckily, I prepared double-flavor hotpot.
還好我準備了鴛鴦鍋
Look the spicy soup and the non-spicy soup.
你看這紅湯和白湯
They have completely different flavors,
明明不能相容 步調不一
yet they are put in the same pot.
卻非要放在一個鍋裡
Since you like spicy food,
你喜歡吃辣
wouldn't it be better
整鍋都是紅湯
if you got a spicy hotpot?
豈不更好
you can't eat any.
你不就不能吃了
Plus,
再說了
the fun part about having hotpot is eating it together.
火鍋就是要大家一起吃才有意思
As the so-called "Seek agreement while shelving differences,"
所謂 求同存異
people with different opinions
誰說立場不同
can certainly get along.
就不能融洽了
Double-flavor hotpot must include two flavors.
鴛鴦鍋就是要紅湯跟白湯在一起
Neither of the two can be missing.
少了哪一個都不行
Come on, start eating.
你快點吃吧
If you don't eat,
你要是再不吃
I'll have them all.
可就沒有了
Oh, I see!
我知道了
You want wine, right?
你想喝酒對不對
I've prepared fruit wine.
我準備好了 果子露
I know with your heart condition, you can't drink wine.
我知道有心疾不能喝酒
But the fruit wine
所以這種果子露
contains very little alcohol, it won't make you drunk.
酒精度低 不會醉的
It's a special day today,
今天日子特殊
I'll drink a little, too.
我也就略飲薄酒
Toast to you!
敬少君
Okay!
好
Cheers, Your Highness!
韓某敬三公主
Can't believe
真是沒想到
that we can sit here and drink together.
還能坐下來跟你好好喝一杯酒
Here.
來
Banana,
香蕉
let me toast to you again!
我再敬你
Thank you for sparing the orange's life!
感謝你饒了橙子一命
Cheers!
幹
Don't worry.
你放心
You have me.
有我在
I won't watch you die.
絕對不會看著你去死的
There must be a miracle!
一定會出現奇蹟的
If there's not, I'll create one!
沒有奇蹟我也會創造奇蹟
In fact, I've found a way to cure my disease.
其實我已經找到了治病的方法了
But I don't want to use that.
可我不想那麼做
The Third Princess
三公主對韓某
is not guarded against me at all.
當真沒有半點防備